Joseph Wetton

Portland, Oregon 97201 j@joewetton.com • +1 (503) 512-0704 • LinkedIn: JoeWetton

SUMMARY

A college graduate with experience in programming, system design, and data analysis. Demonstrated ability to translate business problems into technical solutions and finally to implementation. Detail oriented with ability to communicate effectively in a team environment.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Nike Inc., Beaverton, Oregon

• Software Engineer, Enterprise Finance Solutions

Sep 2018 – Present

- · Conducted analysis, data modeling and made cloud architecture decisions to enable data flow between many systems.
- Developed CRUD REST API's utilizing a serverless architecture, integrated by other teams within Nike to production.
- Created a continuous delivery pipeline for these API's enabling sub-minute releases to AWS with zero downtime.
- · Built test automation framework to execute during API deployments ensuring consistent functionality across releases.
- Integrated Okta Oauth Scope authorization to ensure utmost data and API endpoint security.
- Owned and developed an entire ETL (Extract, Transform, Load) pipeline and process to archive Nike's legacy finance
 file retention application. Involved identifying and extracting millions of accounts payable and receivable files
 spanning a decade from closed source proprietary system and uploading content into a modern API based digital
 asset management platform. Required analysis, solution design and execution.

TrueCar Inc., Santa Monica, California

• Software Engineering Intern, Post-Prospect User Experience Team

Jun 2017 - Dec 2017

- Wrote unit tests in Ruby for frontend and backend services, as part of a full stack team.
- Managed AWS infrastructure and continuous deployment practices.
- · Built process for automated regression tests using Selenium web framework, MiniTest, Docker and Jenkins.

Intel Inc., Hillsboro, Oregon

Software Engineering Intern, Silicon Validation Group

Apr 2016 – Sep 2016

- Wrote regression tests in Python using pytest framework used in Intel's silicon validation platform.
- Implemented Bullseye software to measure code coverage of silicon validation platform
- Optimized regression run times using synchronous nodes to execute runs reducing time to complete by up to 50%.
- Project Management Assistant, Thunderbolt Technology Group

Mar 2014 – Aug 2015

- Managed Drupal powered marketing and engineering websites.
- Facilitated communication between Thunderbolt host/device product and Intel engineers via email and events.
- Created mobile web application to manage Thunderbolt Developer Conference (Plugfest)

Portland State University, Portland, Oregon

■ Teaching Assistant, Elements of Software Engineering

Mar 2017 – Jun 2017

• Assisted professor with class material which detailed the process of waterfall and agile methodologies for students new to software engineering and facilitated group student interactions.

EDUCATION

Portland State University, Portland, Oregon

■ B.S. in Computer Science (ABET accredited)

Sep 2013 - Jun 2018

Lead Developer/Product Owner - Senior Project

Jan 2018 – Jun 2018

- Product owner of id.ly a cross platform mobile application, self-sovereign identification system and E2E encrypted
 messenger. Developed by a collaboration of 7 students using an agile development style. Incorporated AES & RSA
 encryption, Javascript, React Native, Jira & Git.
- Open Source: https://github.com/bnelson777/id.ly

Java Group Project, Introduction to Performance Measurement

Apr 2017 – Jun 2017

- Designed with 2 other student peers a Java program to simulate bandwidth overhead of log packets over a local network between nodes running synchronously.
- Did statistical analysis on packet overhead measurements based on numerous traffic patterns.

SKILLS

Expert: Python, Java, C++, Ruby, MySQL, HTML, CSS, PHP

Intermediate: C, AWS, Javascript (React/React Native/Node), Elasticsearch, Git

Basic: Swift, Objective-C, C#, Haskell, MS-DOS, Docker

AWARDS

JDI: Just Do It Award Nominee 2020: Recognition of excellence and commitment to Nike's maxims. **1st Place Innovation Challenge:** VersionOne Scanner Mobile App built in React Native that allows bulk updating of agile stories. The app utilized the phones camera and scans QR code's on stories on boards. **Judges Award Innovation Challenge:** Slackbot that allows Nike Employees to get notified when a shoe goes up for sale in their size. Utilizes AWS Lambda/API Gateway/DynamoDB & Slack API.